Register to the Nathaniel Weyl Papers, 1920-2004
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1937-1984; 2-14 (Box 2-14: 3)
  - United States. Congress. House. Select Committee on Crime, 1970 (Folder 13: 19)
  - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee on Internal Security (J. G. Sourwine), 1962-1974 (Folder 13: 20)
  - United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1968-1980 (Folder 13: 21)
  - United States. Federal Communications Commission, 1968 (Folder 13: 22)
  - Van den Haag, Ernest, 1968-1970 (Folder 13: 23)
  - Vanderford, Kenneth H., 1962 (Folder 13: 24)
  - Vining, Daniel R., Jr., 1980-1984 (Folder 13: 25)
  - Wechsler, James A., 1953 (Folder 13: 26)
  - Weinstein, Allen (re Alger Hiss), 1974-1978 (Folder 13: 27)
  - Weismann, Elizabeth, 1963-1976 (Folder 13: 28)
  - Wenger, Win, 1969-1971 (Folder 13: 29)
  - Whitcomb, John M., 1968-1970 (Folder 13: 30)
  - White, William L., 1965-1972 (Folder 13: 31)
  - Wiarda, Howard, 1967-1970 (Folder 13: 32)
  - Wilson, Clyde N., 1968-1983 (Folder 14: 1)
  - Wolfe, Bertram D. and Ella, 1965-1971 (Folder 14: 2)
  - World Affairs Council of Philadelphia, 1960 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Wright, David McCord, 1967 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Wright, Frank S., 1968-1969 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Young, Dayton, 1970 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 1962-1971 (Folder 14: 7)
- Speeches and Writings, 1930-2004; 14-42 (Box 14-42: 7)
  Arranged chronologically. Book reviews and letters to the editor by Weyl are grouped at the end
  - The Hegelian Influence on Marx, Croce and Dewey: An Essay on their Social Philosophies, 1930 (Folder 14: 8)
    Written under the pseudonym Stephen Bandolier.
    Typescript
  - The Downfall of British Labor at the Polls, 1931 September/October (Folder 14: 9)
  - Critical Considerations of Equilibrium Interest Theory, 1932 April 2 (Folder 14: 10)
  - The Economic Determination of Price and Cost under Socialism, 1932 May 6 (Folder 14: 11)
  - "The Khaki Shirts: American Fascists," New Republic, 1932 September 21 (Folder 14: 12)
    Printed copy
  - "The Middle Western Farmers on Strike," Revolt, 1932 October (Folder 14: 13)
  - "Organizing Hunger," New Republic, 1932 December 14 (Folder 14: 14)
  - The Counter-Revolution in Germany, circa 1932 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Organizing the Unemployed, circa 1933 (Folder 14: 16)
    Written under the pseudonym John Camel.
  - "This Game Called Reorganization," New York Post, 1937 June-July (Folder 14: 17)
    Ten-part series written under the pseudonym Rector N. West.
    Typescript and printed copies
  - "Swastika over Brazil," Nation, 1937 November 13 (Folder 14: 18)
  - "Brazil's Dictatorship," Nation, 1937 November 20 (Folder 14: 19)
    Unsigned article
  - "West Indies Killer" (re Rafael Trujillo), 1937 (Folder 14: 20)
    Typescript, drafts, and background materials
  - Newspaper articles on economics and Latin America, New York Post, 1937-1938 (Folder 14: 21)
    Some unsigned and one written under the pseudonym Rector N. West
    Printed copies
  - Untitled and unsigned article re Brazil, Nation, 1938 May 21 (Folder 15: 1)
  - "A Plan for Economic Cooperation between the United States and Mexico," speech, International Industrial Relations Institute Congress, Mexico City, 1938 September 3 (Folder 15: 2)
  - "Latin America Faces Fascism," New Republic, 1938 September 28 (Folder 15: 3)
  - "A League of the Americas," Nation, 1938 November 5 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Notes on the Introduction to Keynes' General Theory, 1939 December 5 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Financing the European War, 1939 (Folder 15: 6)
  - The Reconquest of Mexico: The Years of Lázaro Cárdenas (co-author with Sylvia Weyl), 1939 (Folder 15: 7)
    Contract, reviews, and 1960 correspondence re Spanish translation
  - Anarchist Ideals and the Socialist Movement, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 8)
  - Bond Prices and Short Time Interest Rates, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 9)
  - Capital Creation and the Financial Circulation, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 10)
  - The Continuous Character of Inflation, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 11)
  - A Contribution to the Theory of Labor Displacement, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 12)
  - A Criticism of Keynes' Equations of the Price-Level, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 13)
  - The Fallacy of the Keynesian Multiplier, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 14)
  - In Partial Defense of the 'Monetary Crank,', circa 1930s (Folder 15: 15)
  - Incentives to Technical Improvement under Competition and under Monopoly, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 16)
  - Installment Purchase and Income Levels, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 17)
  - John Maynard Keynes: The Dynamics of Monetary Theory, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 18)
  - The Natural Rate of Interest, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 19)
  - The Necessity of a Dynamic Economic Theory, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 20)
  - Notes on economics, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 21)
    Typescripts and holographs
  - On the Possibilities of General Overproduction, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 22)
  - Pricing under Socialist Planning, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 23)
  - A Reconsideration of the Wages Fund Doctrine, circa 1930s (Folder 15: 24)
  - Some Aspects of Derived Demand, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 1)
  - Some Economic Effects of Installment Credit, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 2)
  - Some Monetary Aspects of General Over-Production, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 3)
  - Some Uncoordinated Aspects of the Theory of Wages, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 4)
  - Two Approaches to Equilibrium Theory, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 5)
  - Under What Conditions Is General Overproduction Possible?, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 6)
  - Unemployment in a Socialist State, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 7)
  - The Velocity of Money, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 8)
  - What Is the Middle Class?, circa 1930s (Folder 16: 9)
  - Profits in the Consumption Goods Industries, 1940 January 14 (Folder 16: 10)
  - "Generalisimo de los ejercitos americanos" (co-author with Sylvia Weyl), Americas, 1940 April (Folder 16: 11)
  - "The Prospects of Social Freedom in the United States," speech, League for Industrial Democracy conference, Forest Park, Pennsylvania, 1940 June 15 (Folder 16: 12)
  - "British Colonies Fear Nazi Racialism: Natives Rally to Empire's Defense" and "U.S. Subsidy to Liberal Latin Gov'ts Would Keep All Latin America from Nazis," New Leader, 1940 July 6 and 27 (Folder 16: 13)
  - "Mexico under Cárdenas," American Mercury, 1940 July (Folder 16: 14)
  - "Mexico Faces Revolt before Oct. 1 unless U.S. Openly Backs Avila," New Leader, 1940 September 21 (Folder 16: 15)
  - "U.S. Vital Lines Lay on 3 Fronts: Britain, West Africa and the South Seas," New Leader, 1940 October 12 (Folder 16: 16)
  - "Far Afield" newspaper columns, Kenosha Labor, 1940 (Folder 16: 17)
  - "Forced Migration" (re war refugees), circa 1940 (Folder 16: 18)
  - "Wallace Trip Earned Mexico's Good Will: U.S. Funds Now Needed to Build Nation," New Leader, 1941 January 6 (Folder 16: 19)
  - Murder Mañana (detective novel), 1941 (Folder 16: 20)
    Reviews
  - The Logic of Logistics, 1943 (Folder 16: 21)
    Typescripts
  - The Keynes-Kahn Multiplier, 1945 December (Folder 16: 22)
  - "U.S. Financial Assistance in World Reconstruction," Foreign Commerce Weekly, 1947 February 1 (Folder 16: 23)
  - "The International Bank, an Instrument of World Economic Reconstruction" (co-author with Max J. Wasserman), American Economic Review, 1947 March (Folder 16: 24)
  - "Credo of Freedom" (projected book, uncompleted), 1948 (Folder 16: 25)
    Drafts
  - "Man against Malaria," Américas, 1949 September (Folder 16: 26)
  - The Atomic Bomb and the Pattern of Warfare, circa 1940s (Folder 16: 27)
  - The Changing Face of War, circa 1940s (Folder 16: 28)
  - Design for this Hemisphere, circa 1940s (Folder 16: 29)
  - Equilibrium Exchange Rates in a Partially Controlled Economy, circa 1940s (Folder 16: 30)
  - Lord Keynes' Great Design, circa 1940s (Folder 16: 31)
  - Some Economic Aspects of War Procurement Policy, circa 1940s (Folder 16: 32)
  - Projected pamphlet on Point Four Program, 1950 January 25 (Folder 17: 1)
  - "American Foreign Policy" (projected book, uncompleted), circa 1950 February (Folder 17: 2-3)
  - Notes on Erich Fromm's Escape from Freedom, 1950 March 13 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Fiction and Phantasy, 1950 May 19 (Folder 17: 5)
  - "Treason and Conspiracy in the United States Today: Revealed: How Traitors and the Red Fifth Column Threaten Democratic America's Future," See, 1950 September (Folder 17: 6)
  - Concerning Macro-Economics, 1950 (Folder 17: 7)
  - On Economic Incentives, 1950 (Folder 17: 8)
  - "The Road Back to Free Enterprise" (projected book, uncompleted), circa 1950 (Folder 17: 9)
  - "The Role of International Monetary Agencies," in Glenn E. Hoover, ed., Twentieth Century Economic Thought, 1950 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Treason: The Story of Disloyalty and Betrayal in American History, 1950 (Folder 17-18)
    - Reviews (Folder 17: 11)
    - Reviews (contd.) (Folder 18: 1-2)
    - Printed excerpt: "Benedict Arnold and Wife," Catholic Digest, 1950 September (Folder 18: 3)
  - "The Art of Spy-Catching," Reporter, 1951 January 23 (Folder 18: 4)
  - Economic Notes on Surinam, 1951 May 17 and undated (Folder 18: 5)
    Drafts and working materials
  - "Blood Will Tell," Suspense, 1951 Summer (Folder 18: 6)
  - The Battle against Disloyalty, 1951 (Folder 18-19)
    - Printed copy (Folder 18: 7)
    - Reviews (Folder 19: 1-2)
  - The Customer-Investor Plan, 1951 (Folder 19: 3)
  - Testimony, U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Internal Security, 1952 February 19 and 21 (Folder 19: 4)
    Printed transcript and press coverage
  - "Psychological Strategy and American Foreign Policy: Why Stalin Retains the Propaganda Initiative," SAIS Alumni Review, 1952 Spring (Folder 19: 5)
  - General Feilding's Adventure in Bigamy, circa 1952 September (Folder 19: 6)
  - An Elizabethan Poet in Russia, circa 1952 November (Folder 19: 7)
  - Revolutionary Nihilism and Totalitarian Man, circa 1952 November (Folder 19: 8)
  - Communist Party Strength among American Teachers, circa 1952-1953 (Folder 19: 9)
  - "I Was in a Communist Unit with Hiss: Revelations of a Liberal" (interview transcript), U.S. News and World Report, 1953 January 9 (Folder 19: 10)
  - "The Politician, the Scholar, and Academic Freedom," speech, Howard University Conference on Academic Freedom, 1953 March 12 (Folder 19: 11)
    Typescript and program
  - Cadres, Revolutionists and Bureaucrats, 1953 September 1 (Folder 19: 12)
  - The Genetic Factor and the Rise and Fall of Civilizations, 1953 September 17 (Folder 19: 13)
  - "The Prospects for Peace," Faith and Freedom, 1953 October (Folder 19: 14)
  - "Gold and Subversion," Freeman, 1953 November 16 (Folder 19: 15)
    Typescript, printed copy, and working materials
  - Red Bridgehead in the Guianas, circa 1953 (Folder 19: 16)
  - The Biological Basis of Jewish Intellectual Ability, or Jews, Genes and Genius, 1954 January 11 (Folder 20: 1)
    Outlines and transcripts
  - "Pink-Tinted Knowledge" (re The Reader's Encyclopedia), Freeman, 1954 January 25 (Folder 20: 2)
    Written under the pseudonym Walter Newlin.
    Typescript and printed copy
  - Eugenics and Negro Slavery, 1954 February 15 (Folder 20: 3)
  - "Quarantine of Red Guatemala?" Freeman, 1954 February 22 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Some Peculiarities of Christianity, 1954 May 9 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Red China's Population Crisis" and "The Westward Drive of Soviet China, 1954 (Folder 20: 6)
    Typescripts and working materials
  - "Out of My Political Past" (re Communist Party), 1955 June 25 (Folder 20: 7)
  - Christianity and Civilization, 1956 January 6 (Folder 20: 8)
  - The Anatomy of Terror: Khrushchev's Revelations about Stalin's Regime (Public Affairs Press booklet reprinting text of Nikita Khrushchev speech at 20th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, with an introduction by Weyl), 1956 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Projected book about the United States Constitution (uncompleted), 1956 (Folder 20: 10)
    Notes and working materials
  - King Edward VIII, circa 1957 (Folder 20: 11)
    Typescript and working materials
  - "The Role of Jews in Soviet Science" (projected study to be co-authored with Sylvia Weyl, uncompleted), 1959 February 12 (Folder 20: 12)
    Proposal and working materials
  - "Nobel Scientists: Most Today Are Americans" (projected study, uncompleted), 1959 December 10 (Folder 20: 13)
    Proposal
  - The Mind of an Assassin, 1959 (Folder 20-22)
    Book by Isaac Don Levine, undertaken with collaboration of Nathaniel and Sylvia Weyl
    - Correspondence with Isaac Don Levine, Julian Gorkin, Joseph Hansen, Joaquin Maurin, Maria Orlov and others (Folder 20: 14)
    - Outlines and memoranda (Folder 20: 15)
    - Working materials (Folder 20: 16)
    - Notes (Folder 21: 1)
    - Preliminary drafts (Folder 21: 2-5)
    - Final draft by Nathaniel and Sylvia Weyl (Folder 22: 1-3)
    - Reviews, printed excerpts in Life, and interview with Isaac Don Levine in U.S. News and World Report (Folder 22: 4)
  - "The Character Structure of Communists" (projected study, uncompleted), circa 1950s (Folder 22: 5)
  - "Conspiracy" (projected study of Thomas Henry Hines, Confederate officer involved in so-called Northwest Conspiracy to incite insurrection in Northern states of the Midwest during the American Civil War, uncompleted), circa 1950s (Folder 22: 6)
    Drafts, notes, and background material
  - "Dana's Spy and the Lincoln Murder" (re alleged Confederate involvement in assassination of Abraham Lincoln), circa 1950s (Folder 23: 1)
    Typescript, drafts, notes, and working materials
  - Heredity and Environment, circa 1950s (Folder 23: 2)
  - How to Detect Red Fronts, circa 1950s (Folder 23: 3)
  - The Laws of History, circa 1950s (Folder 23: 4)
  - "The Making of a Communist" (autobiographical vignette), circa 1950s (Folder 23: 5)
  - Projected study of national security (uncompleted), circa 1950s (Folder 23: 6)
  - The Rabbinate: An Experiment in Eugenics, circa 1950s (Folder 23: 7)
  - "The Titus Oates Story" (re so-called Popish Plot in 17th century England), circa 1950s (Folder 23: 8)
    Written under the pseudonym John Warlock.
    Typescript, drafts, and working materials
  - Values of a Free Society, circa 1950s (Folder 23: 9)
  - Latin America, 1960 March 14 (Folder 23: 10)
  - The Negro in American Civilization, 1960 (Folder 23: 11)
    Publisher agreement and correspondence, and reviews
  - "Ethnic and National Characteristics of the U.S. Elite," Mankind Quarterly, 1961 April-June (Folder 23: 12)
  - "Is Castro a Catholic?" (co-author with Uva de Aragón), St. Joseph Magazine, 1961 May (Folder 23: 13)
  - "Dynamics of the American Elite," Mankind Quarterly, 1961 July-September (Folder 23: 14)
  - "Red Strategy in Latin America," speech to unidentified audience, 1961 September (Folder 23: 15)
  - The Communist Movement in Australia, 1961 November 26 (Folder 23: 16)
  - "The Deformed Dictators" (projected study to be co-authored with Stefan T. Possony, comparing Fidel Castro, Adolf Hitler and Napoleon Bonaparte, uncompleted), 1961 (Folder 23: 17)
    Proposal, correspondence, and working and background materials
  - Red Plot against Peru, 1961 (Folder 23: 18)
    Typescript, and working and background materials
  - Red Star over Cuba: The Russian Assault on the Western Hemisphere, 1961 (Folder 24)
    - Publisher correspondence (Folder 24: 1)
    - Working materials (Folder 24: 2-3)
    - Reviews (Folder 24: 4)
    - Publicity materials (Folder 24: 5)
      Includes press releases, press coverage, and printed excerpt ("The Young Castro," Catholic Digest, 1961 May)
  - "Class Origin of Surnames and Achievement," Mankind Quarterly, 1962 January-March (Folder 25: 1)
  - Joao ('Jango') Goulart, 1962 February 11 (Folder 25: 2)
  - "The Battle against Communism," speech, Project Alert, Fort Lauderdale, Florida, 1962 March 29 (Folder 25: 3)
  - "Why We Have Failed to Halt Communism," St. Joseph Magazine, 1962 March (Folder 25: 4)
  - The Jewish Role in the American Elite, Mankind Quarterly, 1962 July-September (Folder 25: 5)
  - "Embargo Cannot Tumble Castro: Tougher President Can Break Stalemate," Manchester Union Leader, 1962 November 21 (Folder 25: 6)
  - "The Alliance for Socialism" (re Alliance for Progress), circa 1962 (Folder 25: 7)
  - Architects, Soldiers and Subversives, circa 1962 (Folder 25: 8)
  - Mexico on the Knife Edge, circa 1962 (Folder 25: 9)
  - The Young Fidel Castro, circa 1962 (Folder 25)
    Study by Emilio Rocamar (acquaintance of Castro in his youth, probable pseudonym), edited and annotated by Weyl
    - Working materials (Folder 25: 10)
    - Holograph, apparently in Weyl's handwriting (Folder 25: 11)
    - Typescript (Folder 25: 12-13)
  - The Geography of Intellect (co-author with Stefan T. Possony), 1963 (Folder 25-27)
    - Working materials (Folder 25: 14)
    - Working materials (contd.) (Folder 26: 1)
    - Drafts (Folder 26: 2-5)
    - Drafts (contd.) (Folder 27: 1)
    - Reviews (Folder 27: 2)
  - I Was Castro's Prisoner, 1963 (Folder 27: 3)
    Book by John Martino, written with collaboration of Weyl.
    Publisher correspondence, reviews, and publicity materials
  - "Living Beyond 100" (projected study, uncompleted), 1963 (Folder 27: 4)
    Correspondence, and working and background materials
  - "National Origins of the Phi Beta Kappa Membership," Names, 1964 June (Folder 27: 5)
  - "Galton on a Chinese Africa," Mankind Quarterly, 1965 April-June (Folder 27: 6)
    Written under the pseudonym Ethelred Nevin.
    Printed copy, and printed reprint in South African Observer (1965 June)
  - "The American Responsibility in Vietnam," debate with James Tedeschi, Florida Atlantic University, 1964 December 8 (Folder 27: 7)
    Mimeographed copy, and press coverage
  - Projected novel about the ancient Hebrew historian Josephus (uncompleted), 1965 (Folder 27: 8)
    Notes and background material
  - The Relationship of Intellect to Race Progress, 1965 (Folder 27: 9)
    Contribution to Symposium on the Future of the American Negro, to be edited by George S. Schuyler. Typescript and correspondence
  - Pan Americana television program broadcast, Miami, Florida, 1966 April 17 (Folder 27: 10)
    Mimeographed transcript (in Spanish), including interview of Weyl
  - Jose Marti Journalistic Prize Award proceedings, Miami, Florida, 1966 May 14 (Folder 27: 11)
    Mimeographed transcript (in Spanish), including participation of Weyl
  - "The Black Brainwash in America," Mankind Quarterly, circa 1966 (Folder 27: 12)
  - The Creative Elite in America, 1966 (Folder 28-30)
    - Name frequency statistical working materials (Folder 28-30)
      - Athletes (Folder 28: 1)
      - Catholic priests (Folder 28: 2)
      - Esthetic elite (Folder 28: 3)
      - Lawyers (Folder 28: 4)
      - Medical directory entries (Folder 28: 5)
      - Mensa members (Folder 28: 6)
      - Military officers (Folder 28: 7)
      - Nobel Prize winners (Folder 28: 8)
      - Phi Beta Kappa members (Folder 28: 9)
      - Scientists (Folder 28: 10)
      - Scottish names (Folder 28: 11)
      - Student directory entries (Folder 29: 1)
      - Who's Who and Who Was Who (Folder 29: 2)
      - Miscellaneous data (Folder 29: 3-4)
      - Miscellaneous data (contd.) (Folder 30: 1-3)
    - Reviews and publicity materials (Folder 30: 4)
  - The Rise and Suppression of the Communist Movement in White Africa, 1967 March 24 (Folder 30: 5)
  - "The Intelligence of White Rhodesians," Intelligence, 1967 March (Folder 30: 6)
  - "Aristocide as a Force in History," Intercollegiate Review, 1967 June (Folder 30: 7)
  - "The Arab World: A Study of Biogenetic Disintegration," Mankind Quarterly, 1967 December 12 (Folder 30: 8)
  - "The Village of the Gifted" (re Villaggio del Superdotato in Sicily), 1967 December 12 (Folder 30: 9)
  - "Mensa, National Origin, and Religion," Intelligence, circa 1967 (Folder 30: 10)
  - "Some Comparative Performance Indexes of American Ethnic Minorities," Mankind Quarterly, circa 1967 (Folder 30: 11)
  - "White Rhodesians: An Unrecognized Intellectual Elite," Mankind Quarterly, circa 1967 (Folder 30: 12)
  - "The Knife Edge between Dissent and Treason," Experiment, 1968 April-May (Folder 30: 13)
  - Thoughts on an Educational Program for Underdeveloped Countries, 1968 November 21 (Folder 30: 14)
  - "Some Possible Genetic Implications of Carthaginian Child Sacrifice," Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1968 Autumn (Folder 30: 15)
    Publisher correspondence, printed copy, and abstract
  - Asian Opportunity, circa 1968 (Folder 30: 16)
  - The Jew in American Politics, 1968 (Folder 30: 17)
  - The Liberal Quasi-Monopoly in the Communications Field: A Proposal for Action, 1968 (Folder 30: 18)
  - "Genetics, Brain Damage and Crime," Mankind Quarterly, 1969 October-December (Folder 30: 19)
    Printed copy, and printed excerpts (South African Observer, 1970 May)
  - "The Potential Role of the Gifted in Underdeveloped Countries," speech, National Association of Gifted Children annual meeting, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1969 November 5 (Folder 30: 20)
  - "Red Missiles in Cuba Now Returned Diplomat Avers," Palm Beach Gold Coasting, 1969 December 31 (Folder 30: 21)
  - "How Not to Write History," in Idus A. Newby, Challenge to the Court: Social Scientists and the Defense of Segregation, 1954-1966, revised edition, 1969 (Folder 30: 22)
    Publisher correspondence and typescript
  - White and Negro 'Gifted' Population in the United States, circa 1969 (Folder 30: 23)
  - Aesthetic Leadership in the United States, circa 1960s (Folder 31: 1)
  - Education of the Gifted: International Terrain, circa 1960s (Folder 31: 2)
  - Political Theories of the Creative Elite, circa 1960s (Folder 31: 3)
  - The World Potential of High Intelligence, circa 1960s (Folder 31: 4)
  - "On Hating the Establishment," Palm Beach Gold Coasting, 1970 January 7 (Folder 31: 5)
  - "The Florida Plan to Save Our Schools" (co-author with Lewis Kapner), Palm Beach Gold Coasting, 1970 March 18 (Folder 31: 6)
    Typescript, printed copy, and reprint (Statesman, 1970 May)
  - "Benjamin Franklin and Restrictive Immigration," Mankind Quarterly, 1970 April-June (Folder 31: 7)
  - "South Africa and Israel: Beleaguered Creative Enclaves," Ideas, 1970 Winter-Spring (Folder 31: 8)
  - "The Human 'Barometer,'" Daily Telegraph Magazine, 1970 June 5 (Folder 31: 9)
    Typescript, galleys and printed copy
  - Speech, Anti-Defamation League workshop, Miami, Florida, 1970 August 23 (Folder 31: 10)
  - "Jewish Intellectual Superiority: Myth or Reality?" Ideas, 1970 Fourth Quarter (Folder 31: 11)
  - "Some Genetic Aspects of Plantation Slavery," Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1970 (Folder 31: 12)
    Publisher correspondence and background material
  - Traitors' End: The Rise and Fall of the Communist Movement in Southern Africa, 1970 (Folder 31-33)
    - Correspondence (Folder 31: 13)
    - Working and background materials (Folder 31-32)
      - General (Folder 31: 14)
        Mainly printed matter
      - Interview notes (Folder 31: 15)
      - International Symposium on Communism conference papers (symposium held in South Africa) (Folder 31: 16)
      - Sidney Bunting (South African communist leader) material (Folder 31: 17)
        Printed matter
      - South African Communist Party documents captured by South African government (Folder 32: 1)
      - Anti-communist acts and reports of South African government (Folder 32: 2)
      - South African subversion trial opening address, 1959 (Folder 32: 3)
      - South African subversion trials, 1964 (Folder 32: 4-5)
        Transcripts, notes and press coverage
    - Drafts (Folder 32: 6)
    - Drafts (contd.) (Folder 33: 1)
    - Reviews and publicity materials (Folder 33: 2)
  - "Reflections on Negro-White Miscegenation," Mankind Quarterly, 1971 January-March (Folder 33: 3)
  - "Racial Differences in the Range of Brain Capacity," Mankind Quarterly, 1971 April-June (Folder 33: 4)